<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Christian Barra</title>
    <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Christian Barra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrisbarra.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
My name is Christian and I am Senior Software Engineer based in Berlin.
My focus is currently on:
 Microservices and event-driven architecture Machine/Statistical learning Ops for microservices and ML Data engineering  I am a proud Pythonista and Python Software Foundation Fellow.
I am currently organizing PyCon DE 2019, that will take place in Berlin, and berlin.python.pizza.
I was a board member of the EuroPython Society, core organizer of 4 editions of the EuroPython Conference and conference chair of EuroPython 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</guid>
      <description>October 2018  Microservices from Day One - Cloves Carneiro Jr. &amp;amp; Tim Schmelmer Kubernetes Microservices with Docker - Deepak Vohra Advanced Microservices - Thomas Hunter II  September 2018  Ask Measure Learn - Lutz Finger &amp;amp; Soumitra Dutta Badass: Making Users Awesome - Kathy Sierra  August 2018  Coders at Work - Peter Seibel Big Data, Big Dupe: A little book about a big bunch of nonsense - Stephen Few Manage your day-to-day - Jocelyn K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code review that never happened</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/the-code-review-that-never-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/the-code-review-that-never-happened/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working as consultant for a mid-sized company in Europe, where my goal is to try to keep their old Django application alive (running Django 1.5.5).

A few weeks ago, it became clear to me that the server running the application was down. Something wasn&amp;rsquo;t working properly, and yet the logs were completely silent.

So I said… well, there must be an except: pass somewhere and I started looking for it (so much for my Friday night…)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let me introduce: __slots__</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/let-me-introduce-slots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/let-me-introduce-slots/</guid>
      <description>Hey there!
Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about slots.
The inspiration for this article comes from a blog post about Python data structures published by Dan Bader and the small iteration we then had on this gist to check their performances.
For all the examples you are going to see I am using Python 3.6.2.
So what are slots? slots are a different way to define the attributes storage for classes in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My to-watch-list from EuroPython 2017</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/my-to-watch-list-from-europython-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/my-to-watch-list-from-europython-2017/</guid>
      <description>So EuroPython 2017 is over!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a tough mission to organize the #EuroPython this year but again it was an amazing experience.
A special thank goes to all the people that have participated in organizing the conference: EuroPython Team.
This is my to-watch-list for EuroPython 2017, probably you can end up with something different, in case you wonder talks are randomly ordered.
1) The encounter: Python&amp;rsquo;s adventures in Africa // Slide I&amp;rsquo;ve met Aisha for the first time during EuroPython 2015, she was an attendee of the DjangoGirls workshop in Bilbao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes, instances and attributes in Python</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/classes-instances-and-attributes-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/classes-instances-and-attributes-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Some days ago I got a simple question.
class A(): x = 1 a = A() b = A() b.x = 11 a.x # ? My answer was wrong but it was the good occasion to pick some books and the reference docs back and spend some hours with the concepts behind: classes, instances, attributes and namespaces.
All the things you are going to read are related to Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker orchestration</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/docker-orchestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/docker-orchestration/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made a blog post about Docker some months ago.
During this time a lot of things changed.
The last version of Docker is 1.5.0-rc4 and Fig project is now docker-compose.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried docker-compose and I think there have been huge improvements in containers orchestration.
Now you can manage simple or complex containers architecture with only a few lines of code.
The only limitation is that containers need to be on the same host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start with Python and some useful resources</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/how-to-start-with-python-and-some-useful-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/how-to-start-with-python-and-some-useful-resources/</guid>
      <description>Python is an awesome language, simple, explicit, readable and powerful.
I spent a lot of time wondering about how to start learning Python, which resources use and what books I should buy.
After this and some money spent on books I want to share my experience:
First of all there’s a lot of free resources so I think it is not useful to invest too much money on books or other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No country for young men</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/no-country-for-young-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/no-country-for-young-men/</guid>
      <description>Do you see the graph above? It&amp;rsquo;s how much Italy will have to pay to somebody (130% of its GDP) and how many young italians are not working.
Our big problem I like to say that if you are a retired person, with a good month cheque, Italy will be a perfect country for you.
Beatiful place, awesome foods, we have mountains, lakes, sea, hills. And the cost of living isn&amp;rsquo;t too high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why, startup quote api and Docker</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/why-startup-quote-api-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/posts/why-startup-quote-api-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>My first blog and my first post.
The reason to start a blog ? The Why ? (I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished reading Start with Why by Simon Sinek&amp;hellip;.)
 Share my experience and projects Learn about your experience and projects  Although in the last 100 years technology improve our lives quality about a 10x factor, we still study/learn in the same way of 2000 years before. Write and read are still the best method to share knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>