<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Christian Barra</title>
    <link>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Christian Barra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
My name is Christian, I am a Senior Software Engineer based in Berlin where I am organizing PyCon DE 2019 and berlin.python.pizza.
 Looking for a consultant or you want to have a course about Python? I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to have a chat about
 My focus is currently on:
 Microservices and event-driven architecture Machine/Statistical learning DevOps for microservices and machine learning Data engineering  I am a proud Pythonista and Python Software Foundation Fellow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/now/</guid>
      <description>I am living in Berlin (Germany) and although is a crazy city I really, really like it.
The long term plan is to spend 8-9 months here and escape the winter in a warmer place, somewhere in Southern Europe.
One of the main reasons to settle down in Berlin was to have more focused time and have less moving around hustle.
I have 3 main areas of focus (yes, they are interrelated):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</guid>
      <description>November 2018  Scrum and XP from the Trenches (2nd Edition) - Henrik Kniberg  October 2018  Microservices from Day One - Cloves Carneiro Jr. &amp;amp; Tim Schmelmer Kubernetes Microservices with Docker - Deepak Vohra Advanced Microservices - Thomas Hunter II  September 2018  Ask Measure Learn - Lutz Finger &amp;amp; Soumitra Dutta Badass: Making Users Awesome - Kathy Sierra  August 2018  Coders at Work - Peter Seibel Big Data, Big Dupe: A little book about a big bunch of nonsense - Stephen Few Manage your day-to-day - Jocelyn K.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>