<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on chrisbarra.xyz</title>
    <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on chrisbarra.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! My name is Christian and I like to build things and share my knowledge.
In the last years I worked as a consultant, software developer and data scientist.
I am a proud Pythonista, PSF Fellow and I spent a big part of the last 5 years growing the Python Community in Europe. I have been a board member of the EuroPython Society, core organizer of 4 editions of the EuroPython Conference and conference chair of EuroPython 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrisbarra.xyz/page/books/</guid>
      <description>July 2018  Piccolo manuale di autodifesa verbale - Barbara Berckhan The Signal and the Noise - Nate Silver The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy - Douglas Adams  June 2018  You Are Not So Smart - David McRaney The quick-start guide for smart non-profit marketing - Christopher Quereau Data Visualization - Andy Kirk  May 2018  Blue Ocean Strategy - W. Chan Kim and Renée Mauborgne The 7 Day Startup - Dan Norris Sprint - Jake Knapp  April 2018  Building microservices - Sam Newman Thinking with data - Max Shron Python Microservices development - Tarek Ziadé  March 2018  Data science for Business - Foster Provost &amp;amp; Tom Fawcett WHY - Samantha Kleinberg Git for Teams - Emma Jane Hogbin Westby Understanding software - Max Kanat Alexander  February 2018  The Rock Warrior&amp;rsquo;s way - Aro Ilgner Espresso lessons - Arno Ilgner Deep work - Cal Newport Manna - Marshal Brain Ted Talks - Chris Anderson  January 2018  Focused and fearless - Shaila Catherine How to teach programming (and other things) - Greg Wilson Word of mouth marketing - Andy Sernovitz Bad Data handbook - Q.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>